César Siguencia

Phone: (646) 457-7006 | Email: cesar.siguencia@gmail.com Location: 600 West 144th St, Apt 1A, New York, NY 10031

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/cesar-siguencia</u>

Full stack web developer with a strong background in education and passionate about developing new technologies. Team player with extensive experience in customer service who prioritizes communication, career development, and organization at any workplace. Biggest strengths include time management, creativity, availability to others, and having a "whatever it takes" attitude towards challenges.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front End: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Handlebars, React

Back End: Node, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, APIs, RESTful, Graph QL, Bcrypt

Development Technologies: GitHub, Heroku, VSCode, Terminal, Insomnia, Apollo

Computer Skills: Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Google Drive, Mac and Windows, Logic Pro, Final Cut Pro, MailChimp

PROJECTS

NFT-Y

github.com/K-G-J/nft-y | nft-y.herokuapp.com

- An NFT collection site for users to save groups, look at NFT data, and interact with other users.
- Role: Back end, database and bcrypt / Tools: NoSQL, Sequelize, JavaScript, Bcrypt

Weather Dashboard

github.com/cesarsiguencia/weather-dashboard | cesarsiguencia.github.io/weather-dashboard

- A weather search application that details conditions of each city along with an interactive search history.
- Role: Sole developer / Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, APIs

Save My Notes

github.com/cesarsiguencia/save-my-notes | frozen-refuge-80298.herokuapp.com/

- Note taking app for saving and deleting user notes using back end technologies.
- Role: Back end developer / Tools: NoSQL, Sequelize, Express, RESTful routes

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mount Carmel-Holy Rosary School, New York, NY

Operations Coordinator

October 2021 - Present

Manage student tuition collection system, financial aid applications, distribution of scholarships, and school data entry. Manage inventory of school technology, money collection, and donations. Serve as the school's main communications body through newsletters, emails, and alerts. Ensures impeccable customer service is provided by all office staff to visitors and parents. Aid for the admissions team, teachers or classroom support when needed.

- Promoted to this position by principal
- Helped create a new staff hall monitor position for teachers to ensure continuous safety and obedience from students in public spaces, which eliminated school property vandalism done by students the year prior.
- Established a new policy before the 22-23 school year to remind families of tuition deadlines and expectations, resulting in a lower tuition delinquency by \$25,000 compared to one year ago.

Operations Associate

November 2018 - October 2021

- Analyzed and collected student data, school metrics, employee payroll, and ensured the school's yearly compliance with Article 43 regulations.
- Aided the director of operations with finances management as well as supply inventory.
- Supported student admissions by aiding in inquiry collection, application follow ups, and new student registrations

EDUCATION

Columbia University Full Stack Web Development, New York, NY

December 2021 - May 2022

- Earned full stack web development certificate.

Bowdoin College, Brunswick, ME

August 2014 - May 2018

Bachelor of Arts: Sociology and Music

- Recipient of the Goldsmith Adams Research Award for a summer study abroad in Beijing.